brussels.be 2019-06-16

# Avis de confidentialité | City of Brussels

The City of Brussels, when processing your personal data, complies with the applicable legislation and in particular the Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the protection of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data (General Data Protection Regulation or GDPR).

This privacy statement informs you about:

  1. The scope of this privacy statement and the City of Brussels as responsible for processing
  2. The way in which the City of Brussels collects personal data and which processing is associated with it
  3. The security of your personal data
  4. Your rights regarding your personal data
  5. References to other websites and social media
  6. Privacy statement updates

## 1\. Scope of this privacy statement and the City of Brussels as responsible for processing

This privacy statement applies to the website of the City of Brussels which is responsible for the processing of your personal data.

## 2\. Way in which the City of Brussels collects personal data and the processing associated with it

### 2.1. Use of the website __[www.brussels.be](http://www.brussels.be/) and cookies

You do not have to register to visit our website. The City of Brussels uses cookies on its website.

Cookies contain small amounts of information and are downloaded to your computer or other device by a server for this website. Your web browser then sends these cookies back to this website every time you visit, so that they recognize you and know which user preferences you have, for example. More information about cookies and how they work can be found at [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/).

Each time you use this website, information can be collected with the help of cookies. By using this website you agree to the use of cookies by the City of Brussels as described here.

 **Strictly necessary cookies**

These are cookies that allow visitors to use certain functions on the site. If the use of these cookies is blocked, some parts of the website may not work correctly. These cookies are only kept for the duration of the visit on our website.

 **Performance cookies**

The website of the City of Brussels uses performance cookies through Google Analytics to understand how each visitor exactly uses the website. The IP addresses of each visitor are anonymized, as a result of which Google Analytics does not have the IP address.

 **How do you control cookies?**

By using this website you agree that we will place cookies on your computer or other device, as explained above. However, you can retain control over cookies and manage them in different ways. Remember that deleting or blocking cookies may affect your experience as a user, and that parts of this website may no longer be fully accessible.

With most browsers you can see which cookies are on your device and you can delete them individually or block cookies from specific or all websites. Remember that all previously indicated preferences will be lost if you delete all cookies.

To disable cookies in a browser, users must perform certain actions that depend on the used browser. Via the web links below you go to the correct page of the browser you use:

### 2.2. Personal information provided by yourself

You provide personal information when you complete an online form.

The personal data you provide will only be used for the purpose as described in the form. You can fill in forms for an application, an application for a grant, participation in a competition,...

Your personal data will be stored for a limited period of time unless legal provisions require a longer storage period.

To receive the newsletter of the City of Brussels, enter your e-mail address and you will receive an e-mail with the request to click a link to confirm. This double 'opt-in' ensures the City of Brussels that you are the right recipient. With each newsletter you receive, you have the opportunity to unsubscribe.

Please note the following information regarding the newsletter of the City of Brussels. The City of Brussels uses so-called 'tracking technologies' to determine whether you have read or clicked on certain e-mails from the City of Brussels.

The City of Brussels uses MailChimp to track e-mails (for example: e-mail address that was communicated to receive newsletters). MailChimp stores personal data in the United States of America and is certified under the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Data can be communicated by MailChimp to third parties.

You can consult the MailChimp privacy policy on the following web link:

If you do not want the City of Brussels to know whether you have opened, forwarded or clicked on our messages, then you must unsubscribe as it is not possible for the City of Brussels to send these e-mails without this tracking function. You can unsubscribe at any time by following the instructions in the e-mails received from the City of Brussels.

## 3\. Security of your personal data

The City of Brussels does everything possible to protect your personal data, in particular to prevent them from being distorted, damaged or communicated to unauthorized third parties.

Although we have taken the necessary security measures to protect your personal data, it is not possible to exclude an incident in transferring data (via the internet or e-mail).

## 4\. Your rights regarding your personal data

### 4.1. You have the right to:

  * receive information about the processing of your personal data
  * inspect the personal data we hold about you
  * request the correction of inaccurate or incomplete personal data
  * request that personal data be erased if they are no longer needed or if their processing is unlawful
  * object to the processing of your personal data for marketing purposes or for reasons related to your personal situation
  * request in specific cases a restriction on the processing of your personal data
  * receive your personal data in machine-readable form and forward it to another controller ('transferability of data')

### 4.2. You can exercise your rights as follows

To exercise your rights, you must contact the City of Brussels who acts as controller. You must exercise your rights in writing and identify yourself.

You can address your application to the Data Protection Officer at the following address:

  *  **By mail:** City of Brussels, Administrative Centre, Boulevard Anspach 6 - 1000 Brussels, Belgium (to the attention of Privacy)
  *  **By e-mail:** __[privacy@brucity.be](mailto:privacy@brucity.be)

If you send the City of Brussels your request by e-mail, the City will also reply you by e-mail.

In accordance with the GDPR, the City of Brussels will respond to your request within a period of 30 days from the moment that the City is in possession of all the elements necessary for its treatment. If your application is complex, this period may be extended by a maximum of 2 months, but in such a case the City will inform you in advance.

For more information about how your personal data are processed, you can contact the Data Protection Officer directly via the above address or e-mail address.

If you are not satisfied with the way in which the City of Brussels processes your personal data or you believe that your rights have been violated, you can also contact the Data Protection Authority:

  *  **by mail:** Rue de la Presse 35 - 1000 Brussels
  *  **by e-mail:** __[contact@apd-gba.be](mailto:contact@apd-gba.be)

### 4.3. You have knowledge of an incident or you suspect a data breach

As a controller, the City of Brussels assumes its responsibility and requests you to express your concerns in case of suspicion of problems concerning the processing of personal data.

You can send an e-mail to __[privacy@brucity.be](mailto:privacy@brucity.be) if you have incorrectly received an e-mail or you suspect that personal data has been leaked, lost or modified. The City of Brussels is pleased to hear from you as many details as possible in order to be able to handle your message as well and efficiently as possible.

## 5\. References to other websites and social media

 **Social media buttons**

This website uses 'social media buttons' so that users can share web pages or save them as favorites. These are buttons for social media websites of third parties and those websites can store information about your activities on the internet, including your activities on this website.

Read the relevant terms of use and the privacy policy of those sites carefully so that you know exactly how they use your data and find out how you can unsubscribe or delete such data.

 **External web services**

Sometimes the City of Brussels uses external web services on this website to display content, such as images or videos, or to conduct a poll within this website. As with the social media buttons, the City of Brussels can not prevent these sites, or external domains, from collecting information about your use of this 'embedded' content.

## 6\. Changes to the privacy statement

The City of Brussels reserves the right to modify this privacy statement at any time and for any reason. Each change implies an adjustment of the modification date (as indicated at the bottom of this page). The modified rules therefore apply from the date of adjustment.

 _Last update: 1 August 2018_
